FRANCHESKA GUZMÁN FLORES

Software Tester



Carolina, PR



787-410-9414



francheska.dev



francheska-guzman@outlook.com

About

Francheska has 8+ years of combined experience in manual and automated software testing, quality assurance, and web development. ISTQB/ASTQB Certified Tester with strong analytical skills, problem solver, detail-oriented, and interpersonal abilities.

Skills

Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Java, Selenium, Cypress, Mocha, Cucumber, Gherkin Language, WordPress, React.js, Node.js, Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite (PowerMapper), Wave, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Heroku.

Languages: Spanish (native), English (intermediate).

Work Experience

Abarca Health LLC - Pharmacy Benefit Management (PBM) Company Software Test Engineer II

San Juan, PR Apr 2022 - Present

INVID LLC - Information Technology Company OA Tester II

San Juan, PR Apr 2021 - Apr 2022

All previous duties and responsibilities plus:

- Provided training of manual testing activities.
- Contributed to the creation of guidelines to improve internal procedures.

QA Tester I Oct 2019 - Apr 2021

- Participated in the process of the Software Development Life Cycle (Agile/Scrum).
- Performed static testing in requirements and design (mockups).
- Created test plans, test suites, and test cases in Azure Test Plans.
- Ran manual tests and performed exploratory testing in web and mobile applications.
- Conducted usability/accessibility testing for WCAG 2.1, ADA, and Section 508 compliance by using tools such as the Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite, and Wave.
- · Reported and tracked issues identified during testing activities to ensure defect resolution and testing completion.
- · Collaborated in the development of new ideas to resolve system issues and improve current
- Basic query execution over the Microsoft SQL Server database.

New York Film Academy - School of Film and Acting Front End Web Developer

New York, NY

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

- · Coded e-mail marketing campaigns and landing pages based on mockups and provided content.
- Segmented mailing lists by making queries on the database.
- · Delivered approved e-mail campaigns to the target market using both Campaigner and iContact e-mail marketing automation platforms.
- Made updates to the New York Film Academy websites and WordPress sites.
- Coded the new version of the online applications.
- Debugged e-mail campaigns, landing pages, online applications, and websites.
- · Kept track of workflows on Asana and worked closely with the Development, Design, and Marketing teams.

Second Language Design - Creative and Marketing Agency Web Developer

New York, NY Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

- Maintained active communication with the team of designers, developers, and clients such as The North Carolina State University's College of Veterinary Medicine (https://painfreecats.org) and Acupuncture Remedies (https://aprpc.com).
- Developed WordPress sites for clients based on mockups and provided content.
- Performed QA testing across modern platforms and devices.
- Added meta tags for SEO and set up Google Analytics.
- Used Google Spreadsheets API for data collection.
- Delivered the website to the client in their private hosting provider.

uTest - Crowdsourced Software Testing Community Software Tester

Remote

Sep 2014 - Jul 2018

- Executed test cases in web and native applications.
- Performed exploratory testing to identify any GUI, functional, or technical bug.
- Performed localization testing by verifying translations from English to Latin American Spanish.
- Submitted detailed bug reports.

Projects

Weather Forecast

https://francheska-guzman.github.io/weather-forecast

Weather Forecast is a web app that provides information such as temperature, pressure, and humidity of five cities. Developed with React.js and requesting the data from a third party API.

Education

Web Development Immersive Program

2017

Certificate of Completion

New York, NY

General Assembly

Web Development CodeBridge Program

2017

Certificate of Completion

Bronx, NY

Per Scholas

Bachelor of Business Administration

2015

Accounting and Office Systems Administration

San Juan, PR

University of Puerto Rico, Río Piedras Campus

Certifications

Certified Tester, AT*SQA Testing Essentials

Association for Testing and Software Quality Assurance, Inc. (AT*SQA)

Credential ID: 21-AT*Essentials-00008-USA

Issued Dec 2021 - No Expiration Date

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Credential ID: I041-2121

Issued Nov 2021 - No Expiration Date

Certified Tester, Foundation Level (CTFL)

American Software Testing Qualifications Board, Inc. (ASTQB)

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 21-CTFL-01698-USA Issued Sep 2021 - No Expiration Date

https://atsga.org/certified-testers/profile/68f29f4f903049f5b415aa0280400854